Guide to the Time Inc. Time Publishing and Business Records 1929-1999 MS 3009-RG 24
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Advertising Sales Department Records, 1927-1974; 3.5 Linear feet in 4 record cartons including 21 reels of microfilm
  - Subseries V.B. Advertiser Record Cards, 1927-1974; 2.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons including 21 reels of microfilm
    For the microfilm, advertisers are divided into the domestic and international editions. The domestic advertisers are on ten reels and list advertisers from the original American edition. The international advertisers are on eleven reels and list advertisers from the various international editions such as Canada, Asia, SoPac, Latam, and Atlo. Each record card contains the date of issue for the advertisement, size of ad, if it is in black-and-white or color, and the cost. size of ad, if it is in black-and-white or color, and the cost.
    Physical cards from 1974 are divided into Demographic, Metropolitan, National, and Regional. These cards are an example of the cards that were microfilmed. The cards list the advertiser, salesman, and advertising agency.
    Adv. Contr. Hist. Rep. are on microfiche and might be duplicates of the 1974 physical cards or might be another report on advertisers. The abbreviation could mean Advertising Contract History Report. This microfiche was found with the 1974 cards.
    These records remain in the original order. The microfilm was stored together, and the physical cards were stored with the microfiche.
    The microfilm is grouped by domestic and international. Within each group, the imaged cards are organized alphabetically by the name of company or organization placing ad, not by the name of the product.
    The physical cards are in four original groups which have been placed in alphabetical order. Within each group, cards are organized alphabetically by the name of company or organization placing ad, not by the name of the product. The microfiche is at the end as a possible duplicate of the physical cards and remains in the original chronological order.
    - Domestic Advertisers (microfilm), 1927-1968 (Offsite-box 3324)
    - International Advertisers (microfilm), 1941-1970 (Offsite-box 3324)
    - Domestic: Demographic, 1974 (Offsite-box 3327, Folder 1-2)
    - Domestic: Metropolitan, 1974 (Offsite-box 3327, Folder 3-8)
    - Domestic: National: A-R, 1974 (Offsite-box 3327, Folder 9-11)
    - Domestic: National: S-Z, 1974 (Offsite-box 3328, Folder 1)
    - Domestic: Regional, 1974 (Offsite-box 3328, Folder 2-4)
    - Adv. Contr. Hist. Rep. (microfiche), 1974 (Offsite-box 3328, Folder 5-10)
- Series VI. Circulation Department Records: Director Bernhard M. Auer Files, 1936-1960; 0.25 Linear feet in 1 record carton
  Bernhard "Bernie" M. Auer was Time Circulation Manager from at least 1949 through 1955. In the earliest retained Department Head List from 1949 in the Time Inc. Reference Files, this position is listed under the Time Inc. Circulation Department. By 1951 the corporate department has disappeared, and the position is overseen by the magazine. By April 1959, he is signing as Circulation Director. Auer is promoted to Time Publisher in 1960.
  Circulation Director Bernhard "Bernie" Auer's files include additional material included in Time or sent out separately from the magazine along with several subscriber surveys, mainly for new subscribers. The surveys included questions on behaviors and demographics such as age, marital status, and income in an attempt for Time to understand who wanted the magazine and how to appeal to future subscribers.
  - Art Book (Three Hundred Years of American Painting), 1957-1960 (Offsite-box 3290, Folder 1-2)
  - Elections: Convention Booklet, 1952 (Offsite-box 3290, Folder 3)
  - Elections: Convention Guidebook, 1952-1956 (Offsite-box 3290, Folder 4-5)
  - Elections: Election Year Argument Settler, 1956 (Offsite-box 3290, Folder 6)
  - New Subscriber Surveys, 1936-1950 (Offsite-box 3290, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Production and Ad Records Department Records: International Ad Files, 1982-1988; 12 Linear feet in 12 record cartons
  Staff who created or received these records include International Ad Records Manager Robert Parlapiano and International Ad Production Manager Thomas Crusie, both part of the Production and Ad Records staff according to the Time Inc. Department Head Lists in the Time Inc. Reference Files; along with Angela Licausi and Martin Barbieri, listed in the records as responsible for international accounts. Parlapiano is also listed as responsible for international accounts so it is presumed Licausi and Barbieri are part of Production and Ad Records.
  Records include correspondence to and from companies and their agency representatives, invoices, insertion orders for ad campaigns and ad placements; along with and lists of corporations, products and insertion dates and files on special section advertisements. While the staff handle the international ads, there are insertion orders that list placements for domestic editions along with the international editions of for all editions of Time.
  The Advertisers files represent over 500 companies. If a major company existed in the 1980s, it is probable that a files exists for it. Examples of companies include Apple, BMW, British American Tobacco, Hyatt, IBM, ITT Sheraton Corporation, Heineken, Honda, Japan Airlines, KLM Royal Dutch, Kuwait Airways, Lombard North Central, Martini & Rossi, Matsushita Electric, Minolta, New Zealand Post Office, Ricoh, Rolex, and Rupert International.
  There are gaps in the alphabetical ranges of Advertisers files. Files marked as from 1983 contain some records from late 1982. Files marked as from 1988 contain some records from late 1987. One folder from 1984 was found among the 1988 files and moved to its chronological location.
  This series is organized chronologically by year and alphabetically within each year. Some companies were filed by the last name of the purveyor instead of by the full name of the company (e.g., Henry Birks & Sons Ltd.)
  The arrangement is basd on the original order of the Advertiser files which were grouped by year then alphabetically arranged within each year instead of having continuous client files. Files other than Advertiser files were originally in no order.
  - 1982: Advertising Lists: General (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 1-7)
  - 1982: Advertising Lists: Canada (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 8)
  - 1982: Advertising Lists: Changes or Omissions (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 9)
  - 1982: Advertisers: House Ads (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 10)
  - 1982: Advertisers: Media Networks, Inc. (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 11)
  - 1982: Advertisers: Time Book-of-the-Month Club (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 12)
  - 1982: Advertisers: Time Circulation (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 13)
  - 1982: Advertisers: Time-Life Books (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 14)
  - 1982: Advertisers: Xerox-Zureg Inc. (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 15-28)
  - 1982: Special Sections (Offsite-box 3266, Folder 29-32)
  - 1982: Special Sections (Offsite-box 3267, Folder 1-25)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Abbot Laboratories-Allied Van Lines (Offsite-box 3267, Folder 26-76)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Amaretto di Saronno-Henry Birks & Sons Ltd. (Offsite-box 3268)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Blueport A.C.T. (NZ) Ltd.-Canadian National (Offsite-box 3269)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Canadian Pulp and Paper-John Cawsey; Haggie-IBM (International Business Machines Corporation) (Offsite-box 3270)
  - 1983: Advertisers: IBM (International Business Machines Corporation)-K. Hattori and Co. (Offsite-box 3271)
  - 1983: Advertisers: KLM (Airline)-McWilliams Wines NZ Ltd. (Offsite-box 3272)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Meaghers-Odlum Brown (Offsite-box 3273)
  - 1983: Advertisers: OECA (Ontario Educational Communications Authority)/TV-Ramada Inns (Offsite-box 3274)
  - 1983: Advertisers: Ramlosa-Rupert; Stuart Alexander; Thomas Hardy & Sons; William Mara Company (Offsite-box 3275, Folder 1-52)
  - 1984: Advertisers: British American Tobacco (Offsite-box 3275, Folder 53)
  - 1988: Advertisers: Acer Incorporated-Air Rianta (Offsite-box 3275, Folder 54-73)
  - 1988: Advertisers: Akzo Chemical Corporation-Caltex (Offsite-box 3276)
  - 1988: Advertisers: Calvert Empresa de Bebidas Ltda-Export Processing Zones Authority; L.L.Bean (Offsite-box 3277)
- Series VIII. Time Education Program Files, 1967-1980; 6 Linear feet in 6 record cartons, 1 flat box
  The Time Education Program was a subscription service that published teaching aids for educators focusing on content within Time magazine. It was designed for and geared toward the high school level. An October 1972 issue of FYI reports on the the program moving from Corporation Circulation Promotion to Time Promotion. Invoices from 1979 have stamps of payment from Corporate Circulation so it isn't clear if the program stayed within Time with corporate support or moved back to a corporate department.
  Time Education Program Files include the correspondence and administrative records documenting the running of the program and the mailings sent out to subscribers.
  Subseries VIII.A. Correspondence
  Subseries VIII.B. Administrative Files
  Subseries VIII.C. Mailings
  - Subseries VIII.A. Correspondence, 1970, 1977-1979; 0.2 Linear feet in 3 folders
    The majority of correspondence come from Cindy Stump, Mary Fowler and Brenda Blackwood. In 1977 the records identify Stump as manager of the TEP. In 1978 the records identify William J. Miller, Jr. as the manager. In 1979 the records identify Fowler as manager. Correspondence primarily has comments from subscribers, requests for program publications and multimedia kits, and responses from the program.
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 2-3)
  - Subseries VIII.B. Administrative Files, 1967-1980; 4 Linear feet in 4 record cartons
    The majority of records in the Administrative Files come from Cindy Stump, Mary Fowler and Brenda Blackwood. Many memoranda are addressed to Bill Peters. The records document publication creation, budgets and billing, and the program's booth presence at education conventions.
    - General, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 4-5)
    - Ad Proofs, 1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 6)
    - Advertising, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 7-8)
    - Agent Subs (Teacher Information), 1968 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 9)
    - Blue Chip List, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 10)
    - Budget, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 11-13)
    - Canada: General, Sales, and Expenses, 1967-1974 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 14-17)
    - Chicago Rebilled Charges, 1963 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 18)
    - Circulation Department Budget Reports, 1970 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 19)
    - Competition (Other Education Programs), 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 20-21)
    - Conventions, 1968-1980 (Offsite-box 3278, Folder 22-32)
    - Conventions, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 1-6)
    - Cost Estimates, 1968-1972 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 7-8)
    - Current Affairs Test, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 9-12)
    - Delivery Problems, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 13)
    - Domestic Sales, 1974 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 14)
    - Drugs Booklet: Correspondence, 1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 15)
    - Drugs Booklet: Reports, 1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 16-19)
    - "Drugs and the Young" Teaching Aid, 1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 20-21)
    - Editions: Time Asia, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 22)
    - Editions: Time Atlantic, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 23-25)
    - Editions: Time Canada, 1970 (Offsite-box 3281, Folder 26)
    - Editions: Time SOPAC, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 1)
    - Editions: Time Latin America, 1969 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 2)
    - Educators, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 3)
    - English Program, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 4)
    - Estimate Orders, 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 5-9)
    - Expenses, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 10-11)
    - First Half Effort Analysis, 1969 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 12)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 13)
    - Franklin Square, 1968 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 14)
    - International: Budget, Expenses, Promotion, 1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 15-18)
    - Invoices, 1977 March-1979 June (Offsite-box 3282)
    - Invoices for Teaching Aids, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 19)
    - Mail, 1970-1972 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 20-21)
    - Mail Plans, 1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Lists, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 23)
    - Modulearn, Inc., 1977 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 24)
    - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) Summer Institute Mailing, 1967 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 25)
    - New Business Mailing, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 26-29)
    - Orders Received, 1970 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 30)
    - Printing Requisitions, 1977 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 31)
    - Promotional Mailing, 1974 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 32-33)
    - Renewals, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 34)
    - Retreat Information, 1962-1968 (Offsite-box 3279, Folder 35)
    - Sales, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 1-3)
    - Sales Reports, 1967 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 4)
    - Social Studies and English, 1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 5)
    - Student Entries for "Fragments", 1977 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 6)
    - Teachers' Guide, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 7)
    - Teachers' Guide Questionnaire, 1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 8)
    - Teaching Aids, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 9)
    - Teaching Mailing Instructions, 1974 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 10)
    - Testing, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 11)
    - "Time All Summer" Mailing, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 12)
    - Time Index, 1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 13)
    - Time Life International, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 14)
    - Transparencies: GAF Corp., 1969? (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 15)
    - Transparencies: The Hibbert Co., 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 16)
    - Transparencies: Mazer Corporation, 1969 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 17)
    - Upward Bound Orders, 1968 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 18)
    - Wrap Up Reports, 1969-1976 (Offsite-box 3280, Folder 19-28)
  - Subseries VIII.C. Mailings, 1967-1980; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons, 1 flat box
    Mailings contains the material sent to subscribers to the Time Eduation Program including Teachers' Guides to Time and teaching aids. Teachers' Guides to Time in the form of newsletters published weekly concurrently with issues of the magazine. They include summaries of the magazine, teaching points, and bibliographies. Teaching aids are a small topical magazines on current events or ideas such as nuclear power, presidential primaries, utopia, China, and Islam. They include a editor's note, articles, teaching strategies, a bibliography, posters and other handouts, and sometimes a quiz. Some issues contain evaluations of the materials for educators to complete.
    - Teachers' Guides to Time, 1967 September-1970 March (Offsite-box 3283, Folder 1-89)
    - Teaching Aids, circa 1970-1980 (Offsite-box 3283, Folder 90-93)
    - Teaching Aids, circa 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 3284)
    - Teaching Aids, circa 1977 (Offsite-box 3040, Folder 5)